Germain Vallverdu

Associate Professor -- PhD in Chemical Physics



10 août 1983, France Maried, 2 children

Contact

germain.vallverdu@univ-pau.fr (33) 5 59 40 78 51 (33) 6 88 59 08 87

> IPREM Technopôle Hélioparc 2 ave du Président P. Angot FR-64053 Pau cedex 9

Theoretical Chemistry

Computational strategy
Development
Surfaces, interfaces
VASP, CRYSTAL (solid)
Gaussian, Orca (molecule)
Gromacs, AMBER (dynamic)

Programming

Fortran, C Python MET_EX, HTML/CSS

Languages

French English (Professional)

Bibliometry

15 articles 11 conferences h-index: 7 12.5 citations per item 150 citations (142 w/o self-citations)

On the web

orcid.org/0000-0003-1116-8776 •• gVallverdu •• gvallver.perso.univ-pau.fr

Abstract

Associate professor at the Université de Pau et des Pays de l'Adour, I am a theoretical chemist at IPREM institute (Institute for Analytical sciences and chemical physics applied to environment and materials). My research activities concern the development of new methods in theoretical chemistry and new computational strategies at different time or space scales, applied to the investigations of complex systems. I teach mainly chemical-physics subjects and programming languages at the university of Pau.

Professional Experiences

since 2010 Université de Pau et des Pays de l'Adour

Pau, France

Associate professor

Theoretical chemistry and computational approaches. Surfaces, interfaces, reactivity and molecular interactions.

2009-2010 **CEA - DAM**

Bruyères le châtel, France

Postdoctoral position

Development and implementation of a mesoscopic model for reactive shock waves propagation in heterogeneous systems.

2006-2009 Université Paris-Sud 11

Orsay, France

PhD Student

Theoretical study of photophysical processes in fluorescent proteins.

Education

2006-2009	PhD in chemistry speciality theoretical chem Mention très honorable	iistry Université Paris-Sud 11
2004-2006	Master degree of chemistry speciality molecular chemical-physics Mention TB	Université Paris-Sud 11
2003-2004	Bachelor Degree of chemical-physics Mention TB	Université Paris-Sud 11
2003-2006	Magistère de Physico-Chimie Moléculaire	Université Paris-Sud 11 – ENS Cachan
2001-2003	Undergraduate physics and chemistry	Lycée François Arago, Perpignan

Main publications

Quesne-Turin, A. et al. Morphology and Surface Reactivity Relationship in the Li1+xMn2-xO4 Spinel with x = 0.05 and 0.10: A Combined First-Principle and Experimental Study. ACS Applied Materials & Interfaces **2017**,

Santos Silva, H. et al. The role of metalloporphyrins on the physical-chemical properties of petroleum fluids. Fuel **2017**, 188, 374–381.

Vallverdu, G. et al. First principle study of the surface reactivity of layered lithium oxides LiMO2 (M = Ni, Mn, Co). Surf. Sci. **2016**,

Guille, E. et al. Possible Existence of a Monovalent Coordination for Nitrogen Atoms in LixPOyNz Solid Electrolyte: Modeling of X-ray Photoelectron Spectroscopy and Raman Spectra. J. Phys. Chem. C **2015**, 119, 23379–23387.

Martin, L. et al. First principles calculations of solid-solid interfaces: an application to conversion materials for lithium-ion batteries. J. Mater. Chem. **2012**, 22, 22063–22071.

Maillet, J. B. et al. Mesoscopic simulations of shock-to-detonation transition in reactive liquid high explosive. EPL **2011**, 96, 68007.

Vallverdu, G. et al. Relation between pH, structure, and absorption spectrum of Cerulean: A study by molecular dynamics and TD DFT calculations. Proteins: Struct., Funct., Bioinf. **2010**, 78, 1040–1054.

Teaching

- Lectures in chemical-physics, theoretical chemistry and programming languages.
- Strong involvement in new information and communication technologies for education
- Science popularization: Quantum mechanics and workshops for school student